You've finally come, my little brother.
드디어 왔구나, 내 동생.
My brother, Chi Wen.
내 동생, 치웬(Chi Wen).
I'm here.
나는 여기 있다.
You are our long-awaited kin
당신은 우리가 오랫동안 기다려온 친척입니다
and the last hope we have left for the world.
그리고 마지막 희망 우리는 세상을 위해 떠났습니다.
What a pity.
정말 안타깝습니다.
We won't be able to watch you grow up
우리는 네가 성장하는 모습을 볼 수 없을 거야
and transform into a dragon.
그리고 용으로 변신합니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
For what?
무엇을 위해?
The last Dragon Deity's Power
마지막 용신의 힘
has dissipated.
소멸되었습니다.
I can't be a dragon anymore.
나는 더 이상 용이 될 수 없습니다.
Besides,
게다가,
I still have fragments of Jiu Ying in me.
내 안에는 아직도 지우잉의 파편이 남아있습니다.
He could manipulate me at any time.
그는 언제든지 나를 조종할 수 있다.
Perhaps this is fate.
아마도 이것이 운명일 것이다.
You can't turn into a dragon.
당신은 용으로 변할 수 없습니다.
But Jiu Ying can't kill me either.
하지만 Jiu Ying도 나를 죽일 수는 없습니다.
He is forever trapped in this dragon body.
그는 영원히 이 용의 몸에 갇혀있습니다.
Is that it?
그게 다야?
You think I'll give up?
내가 포기할 것 같아요?
Chi Wen. You're so naive.
치 웬. 당신은 너무 순진 해요.
Chi Wen.
치 웬.
Are you alright?
괜찮으세요?
I'm fine.
잘 지내요.
Where's Ji Ling?
지링은 어디 있지?
Why didn't he come with you?
그 사람은 왜 당신과 함께 오지 않았나요?
He's the Dragon Deity we picked.
그는 우리가 선택한 용신입니다.
I haven't seen him for a long time.
나는 그를 오랫동안 보지 못했습니다.
Is he alright?
그 사람 괜찮아요?
Ji Ling is at the Shilin Sect.
Ji Ling은 Shilin Sect에 있습니다.
He was originally a little fox at the foot of South Mountain,
그는 원래 작은 여우였습니다 남산 기슭에
all carefree.
모두 평온합니다.
But he swallowed my dragon scale by mistake
그러나 그는 삼켰다 실수로 내 드래곤 비늘
and shouldered a burden too heavy for him.
그리고 그에게는 너무 무거운 짐을 짊어졌습니다.
I can see now.
이제 알 수 있어요.
What a surprise.
놀랐는 걸.
The dragon scale didn't kill me
용의 비늘은 날 죽이지 않았어
and cured my eyes instead.
대신 내 눈을 치료해 주었어요.
It also surprised me
나도 놀랐어
that it was you, little fox, who swallowed my dragon scale.
바로 너였다고, 작은 여우야. 내 용의 비늘을 삼킨 자.
Master Chi Wen, you remember me?
치웬 선생님, 저를 기억하시나요?
Of course.
물론이죠.
Why did you swallow my dragon scale?
왜 내 용의 비늘을 삼켰나요?
I heard that it was a deadly mission
치명적인 임무였다고 들었어
and thought it would kill me.
그리고 그것이 나를 죽일 것이라고 생각했습니다.
That's why I took it.
그래서 내가 가져간 거야.
He's a good man.
그는 좋은 사람이에요.
I owe him my life.
나는 그에게 내 생명을 빚지고 있습니다.
Maybe it was destined
어쩌면 운명이었나봐
by heaven.
천국으로.
Little fox.
작은 여우.
Do you have a name?
이름이 있나요?
From now on, let's call you Ji Ling.
이제부터 당신을 Ji Ling이라고 부르겠습니다.
Ji Ling?
지 링?
Ji Ling.
지 링.
What a nice name.
정말 좋은 이름이네요.
I have a name. Master Chi Wen gave me a name.
나는 이름이 있습니다. Chi Wen 선생님이 제게 이름을 지어주셨어요.
Master Chi Wen,
치웬 선생님,
does this name carry a specific meaning?
이 이름에는 특별한 의미가 있나요?
I heard that names carry meanings
이름에는 의미가 있다고 들었어
in the mortal world.
필멸의 세계에서.
Whoever swallows my dragon scale
내 용의 비늘을 삼키는 자는 누구라도
becomes a vessel for my spirit.
내 영혼을 담는 그릇이 됩니다.
Ji Ling, a spirit vessel.
영혼의 그릇 지링(Ji Ling).
Aren't you afraid?
두렵지 않나요?
If you hadn't saved me,
당신이 나를 구하지 않았다면,
I would have died.
나는 죽었을 것이다.
Why would I be scared to be your spirit vessel
내가 왜 겁을 먹겠는가? 당신의 영혼의 그릇이 되어주세요
to save the world?
세상을 구하기 위해?
I didn't expect
기대하지 않았어
that a little fox could do such a great thing.
그 작은 여우 정말 대단한 일을 할 수 있었어.
So Ji Ling was a vessel for your spirit.
So Ji Ling은 당신의 영혼을 담는 그릇이었습니다.
Then why did you choose to stay here?
그렇다면 왜 이곳에 머물기로 결정하셨나요?
Out of sympathy.
동정심에서.
Yuan Wuhuo was doomed.
Yuan Wuhuo는 운명을 정했습니다.
But Ji Ling showed up unexpectedly.
그러나 Ji Ling은 예기치 않게 나타났습니다.
I couldn't bear to take the life of a kind creature at will.
나는 생명을 앗아가는 것을 참을 수 없었다 마음대로 친절한 생물.
So we changed our plans.
그래서 우리는 계획을 바꿨습니다.
You made Ji Ling the "Dragon Deity".
당신은 Ji Ling을 "용신"으로 만들었습니다.
- Didn't you? - Yes.
- 그렇지 않았나요? - 예.
No one needs to be sacrificed.
누구도 희생될 필요가 없습니다.
I have another way.
다른 방법이 있어요.
Just lend me your demon power.
나에게 악마의 힘을 빌려주세요.
I have plans about how to regain the Dragon Deity's Power.
복원 방법에 대한 계획이 있습니다 용신의 힘.
Greetings, Master Dragon Deity.
안녕하세요, 마스터 드래곤 신님.
I can't go on fooling around.
계속 장난을 칠 수는 없어요.
It's time to grow up.
이제 성장할 시간입니다.
Goodbye, little fox.
안녕, 작은 여우.
I'll miss you.
나는 당신을 그리워할 것이다.
How come you're carrying a fragrance out of nowhere?
왜 들고 다니는 거야? 갑자기 향수?
I bathe with only water and eat vegetarian.
물로만 목욕해요 그리고 채식을 하세요.
There can't be a fragrance.
향기가 있을 수 없습니다.
There is.
있습니다.
But this smell makes people sad,
하지만 이 냄새는 사람들을 슬프게 해요
as if they're hollowed out.
마치 속이 비워진 것처럼.
Autumn days are bleak.
가을날은 쓸쓸하다.
The golden-scale wood is losing all its leaves.
황금비늘나무 잎사귀를 모두 잃어가고 있어요.
The branches look empty.
가지가 비어있는 것 같습니다.
That's why you have the delusion.
그렇기 때문에 당신은 망상을 갖고 있는 것입니다.
If people can live for 100
사람이 100년 동안 살 수 있다면
or 1,000 years, like trees,
또는 나무처럼 1,000년,
that would be nice.
그러면 좋을 것 같아요.
Not really.
설마.
Trees are too lonely.
나무는 너무 외로워요.
For centuries,
수세기 동안
they had to stay put in one place.
그들은 한 곳에 머물러야 했습니다.
That's right.
좋아요.
Little fox.
작은 여우.
You swallowed the dragon scale and obtained immortality.
당신은 용의 비늘을 삼켰습니다 그리고 불멸을 얻었습니다.
But you're neither a human nor a demon,
하지만 당신은 인간도 악마도 아닙니다.
without a single kin.
친족 하나 없이.
You became the loneliest outlier in the world.
넌 가장 외로운 이상치가 됐어 세계에서.
Then you carry the gravest
그럼 당신은 가장 무덤을 가지고
and most hopeless mission,
그리고 가장 절망적인 임무는
trapped in this lonely courtyard.
이 외로운 안뜰에 갇혀있습니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I don't have kin,
난 친족이 없어
but I have friends.
하지만 나에겐 친구가 있어요.
They are by my side, aren't they?
그들은 내 옆에 있지 않습니까?
But people around you
하지만 주변 사람들은
will grow old one by one
하나씩 늙어갈 거야
and perish.
그리고 멸망한다.
It's so cruel.
너무 잔인해요.
You'll stay with me, won't you?
나와 함께 있어줄 거지, 그렇지?
My time has come, too.
내 시간도 왔다.
But the title of Dragon Deity remains a faith
하지만 용신이라는 칭호는 여전히 믿음
as well as a huge burden.
마찬가지로 큰 부담이다.
It's been a century.
한 세기가 지났습니다.
Things must have been hard for him.
그에게는 힘든 일이 있었을 것입니다.
Has he changed?
그 사람이 변했나요?
He…
그는…
is somehow different now.
지금은 뭔가 다르다.
He's no longer that simple little fox.
그는 더 이상 단순한 작은 여우가 아닙니다.
His heart grew much heavier.
그의 마음은 더욱 무거워졌습니다.
His eyes were shrouded,
그의 눈은 가려져 있었다,
impossible to see through.
꿰뚫어 보는 것은 불가능합니다.
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
That's why I came to see you.
그래서 당신을 만나러 왔습니다.
Ji Ling was haunted by his inner demon and fell unconscious.
Ji Ling은 내면의 악마에 사로잡혀 있었습니다. 그리고 의식을 잃었습니다.
Inner demon?
내면의 악마?
Bai Ze said
바이제가 말했다
that it's a demon transformed from your dragon scale,
그건 악마로 변신한 거라고 당신의 용의 비늘에서,
called Ji Can, the Lonescale.
론스케일 지칸(Ji Can)이라고 불린다.
Sorry. I can't help Ji Ling.
죄송합니다. 나는 Ji Ling을 도울 수 없습니다.
No one in the world can defeat a Lonescale,
세상에 누구도 론스케일을 물리칠 수 있어
except for Ji Ling himself.
Ji Ling 자신을 제외하고.
Because a Lonescale is also a dragon.
론스케일도 용이기 때문이죠.
Only dragons
용들만
can kill a dragon.
용을 죽일 수 있습니다.
That's right.
좋아요.
Destiny loves to play tricks.
운명은 장난을 좋아합니다.
If I could
할 수 있다면
trust him more and read his mind earlier,
그를 더 신뢰하고 그의 마음을 더 일찍 읽어보세요
perhaps he wouldn't
아마도 그는 그렇지 않을 것 같아요
be controlled by his inner demon.
내면의 악마에 의해 조종당합니다.
He dressed up as the Dragon Deity.
그는 용신으로 분장했습니다.
Since ancient times, fancy attire has always been a shackle.
고대부터, 화려한 옷차림은 항상 족쇄였습니다.
My intuition tells me that Wu Shiguang is not a bad guy.
내 직감이 말해주네 Wu Shiguang은 나쁜 사람이 아닙니다.
That low-rank weasel demon only stole a gown.
그 하급 족제비 악마 가운만 훔쳤어요.
But he captured him for a reward.
그러나 그는 보상을 위해 그를 잡았습니다.
How is he not bad?
그 사람은 어떻게 나쁘지 않은가?
He was trying to save that weasel demon.
그는 족제비 악마를 구하려고 했어요.
That weasel lacked cultivation.
그 족제비에는 재배가 부족했습니다.
With his current level of power,
그의 현재 권력 수준으로는
he could only wear plain clothes.
그는 사복만 입을 수 있었다.
Silk and satin would be too much for him.
실크와 새틴은 그에게 너무 과할 것입니다.
He would die.
그는 죽을 것이다.
I had no idea.
나는 전혀 몰랐다.
Well then, your clothes are so gorgeous.
그럼 옷이 참 멋지네요.
Can you handle it?
처리할 수 있나요?
He wore the clothes of the Dragon Deity
그는 용신의 옷을 입었습니다
and had to put up with endless loneliness.
끝없는 외로움을 참아야 했습니다.
I feel much better these days.
요즘 기분이 훨씬 나아졌어요.
I want to visit my hometown.
고향을 방문하고 싶습니다.
My parents' tomb hasn't been swept for quite a while.
부모님의 무덤 꽤 오랫동안 청소되지 않았습니다.
Aging and seriously wounded beasts
나이 들고 심각한 상처를 입은 짐승들
always go alone to the hidden caves in the forest
항상 혼자 가세요 숲 속 숨겨진 동굴로
at the end of their lives.
삶의 마지막에.
They don't want their kin to witness their death.
그들은 친족을 원하지 않습니다 그들의 죽음을 목격하기 위해.
That's their last pride.
그것이 그들의 마지막 자부심입니다.
Stop looking for me.
나를 찾지 마세요.
I don't want you to see my ruined look.
망가진 내 모습을 보여주고 싶지 않아요.
Think of it as a final goodbye.
마지막 작별 인사라고 생각하세요.
I didn't achieve anything
아무것도 성취하지 못했습니다
I've ever wanted to achieve
나는 항상 이루고 싶었던 것
throughout my life.
평생
I gained nothing.
나는 아무것도 얻지 못했습니다.
I failed as an older brother.
나는 형으로서 실패했다.
Little fox.
작은 여우.
I have to go now.
이제 가야 해요.
You shouldered
당신은 어깨를 으쓱했습니다
so much burden for me in this life.
이생에서 나에게는 너무 많은 부담이 있습니다.
I owe you way too much.
나는 당신에게 너무 많은 빚을 지고 있습니다.
I can't atone for my sins now.
지금은 내 죄를 속죄할 수 없습니다.
Child.
아이.
You are kind and pure.
당신은 친절하고 순수합니다.
But if there is an afterlife,
하지만 사후세계가 있다면
I hope you can be selfish.
당신이 이기적이기를 바랍니다.
It's getting cold. Let me grab you a gown.
날씨가 추워지고 있어요. 가운을 가져다 드리겠습니다.
Master Chi Wen.
치웬 선생님.
My time has come.
내 시간이왔다.
May I be so shameless
너무 뻔뻔해도 될까요
as to ask you for one thing,
한 가지 부탁을 드리자면,
please?
제발?
I'm listening.
듣고 있어요.
For so many years,
수년 동안
I've been by your side.
나는 당신 옆에 있었어요.
I only see my wife and child
나는 아내와 아이만 본다
on New Year's Eve.
새해 전날.
I take pride in my devotion
나는 내 헌신에 자부심을 느낀다
to the Shilin Sect.
Shilin 종파에.
However,
그러나
I feel guilty to my family.
나는 가족에게 죄책감을 느낀다.
My child wrote to say
우리 아이는
that his mother
그 사람 어머니
doesn't have many days left.
며칠이 남지 않았습니다.
You want me
당신은 나를 원해요
to save your wife?
아내를 구하기 위해?
No.
아니요.
Master Chi Wen.
치웬 선생님.
I just want you…
난 단지 당신을 원해요...
I just want you
난 단지 당신을 원해요
to grant me another day of health
나에게 하루 더 건강을 허락해 주려고
so that I have the strength
내가 힘을 가질 수 있게
to get out of bed,
침대에서 일어나려면
walk out of the Shilin Sect,
스린파에서 나가세요,
and see her once again at home.
그리고 그녀를 집에서 다시 한 번 만나보세요.
Can you fulfill my wish?
내 소원을 들어줄 수 있나요?
Master Chi Wen.
치웬 선생님.
I…
나는…
I can't help you.
나는 당신을 도울 수 없습니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I overstepped.
나는 지나쳤다.
Master Chi Wen.
치웬 선생님.
The Dragon Deity's Power
용신의 힘
should be preserved for those who need it more.
보존되어야 한다 더 필요한 사람들을 위해.
I'll take one step ahead
한 발 앞서 나가겠습니다
and wait for her in the other world.
그리고 다른 세계에서 그녀를 기다리세요.
Master Dragon Deity.
마스터 드래곤 신.
I'm so proud
정말 자랑스러워요
to be able to serve by your side.
당신 곁에서 봉사할 수 있도록.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Yuan Wuhuo
위안 우훠
died.
죽었습니다.
Ye Daoxuan died, too.
예다오쉬안(Ye Daoxuan)도 죽었습니다.
They both
둘 다
left me.
나를 떠났다.
I don't have the Dragon Deity's Power.
나에게는 용신의 힘이 없다.
I'm an imposter.
나는 사기꾼입니다.
I can't fulfill anyone's wishes.
나는 누구의 소원도 들어줄 수 없습니다.
Nor can I
나도
keep anyone around.
누구든지 주변에 두세요.
No one can keep me company forever.
누구도 나와 영원히 함께 할 수 없습니다.
Maybe
어쩌면
this will set me free.
이것이 나를 자유롭게 해줄 것이다.
Don't be sad.
슬퍼하지 마세요.
Don't cry.
울지 마세요.
I will always be with you.
나는 항상 당신과 함께 있을 것입니다.
Don't be sad.
슬퍼하지 마세요.
Don't cry.
울지 마세요.
I will always be with you.
나는 항상 당신과 함께 있을 것입니다.
Don't be sad. Don't cry.
슬퍼하지 마세요. 울지 마세요.
- Wu. - Don't be sad.
- 우. - 슬퍼하지 마세요.
Don't cry.
울지 마세요.
- Is that you? - I will always be with you.
- 당신인가요? - 언제나 함께하겠습니다.
Wu.
우.
Don't be sad. Don't cry.
슬퍼하지 마세요. 울지 마세요.
I will always be with you.
나는 항상 당신과 함께 있을 것입니다.
Who are you?
누구세요?
I'm Lonescale,
나는 Lonescale이야,
the loneliness residing in you,
당신 안에 있는 외로움
your inner demon.
당신의 내면의 악마.
I am you.
나는 당신입니다.
Lu Wuyi severed her spiritual tail
Lu Wuyi가 자신의 영적인 꼬리를 잘랐습니다
and fainted from the pain.
그리고 고통에 기절했다.
Her spiritual tail corresponds to the eyes.
그녀의 영적인 꼬리 눈에 해당합니다.
What?
무엇?
Why did she sever her tail?
그녀는 왜 꼬리를 잘랐나요?
She followed your soul
그녀는 당신의 영혼을 따랐어요
back in time.
시간을 거슬러.
To see everything,
모든 것을 보려면,
she had to attach herself to someone
그녀는 누군가에게 자신을 집착해야 했어
or something.
아니면 뭔가.
Back then,
그때는
I only had Yuan Wuhuo
난 Yuan Wuhuo밖에 없었어
and Ye Daoxuan around.
그리고 주변에는 Ye Daoxuan이 있습니다.
Who was she?
그녀는 누구였나요?
Don't you already know the answer?
당신은 이미 답을 알고 있지 않습니까?
Don't be sad.
슬퍼하지 마세요.
Don't cry.
울지 마세요.
I will always be with you.
나는 항상 당신과 함께 있을 것입니다.
Don't be sad.
슬퍼하지 마세요.
Don't cry.
울지 마세요.
I will always be with you.
나는 항상 당신과 함께 있을 것입니다.
Don't be sad.
슬퍼하지 마세요.
Don't cry.
울지 마세요.
I will always be with you.
나는 항상 당신과 함께 있을 것입니다.
Don't be sad.
슬퍼하지 마세요.
Don't cry.
울지 마세요.
I will always be with you.
나는 항상 당신과 함께 있을 것입니다.
Don't be sad.
슬퍼하지 마세요.
Don't cry.
울지 마세요.
I will always be with you.
나는 항상 당신과 함께 있을 것입니다.
My little fox.
나의 작은 여우.
It was her.
그녀였습니다.
It's always been her.
항상 그녀였습니다.
Let's reciprocate.
보답합시다.
Call me Wu from now on.
이제부터 우라고 불러주세요.
Wu.
우.
The cry of a fox. Wu.
여우의 울음소리. 우.
It has the same name.
그것은 같은 이름을 가지고 있습니다.
It turns out that my Wu
내 우
has always been my Wu.
항상 나의 우였습니다.
Master Daoxuan.
다오수안 선생님.
Since you won't save him,
당신이 그를 구하지 않을 테니
you shall die too.
너도 죽을 것이다.
It's so inconvenient to be a human.
인간으로서 너무 불편해요.
I can't even leave marks.
흔적조차 남길 수가 없어요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Here.
여기.
Have some too.
너도 좀 먹어라.
I left oil on your hands.
나는 당신의 손에 기름을 남겼습니다.
It's fine. I'll wash you later.
괜찮습니다. 나중에 씻어줄게.
You are a little fox.
당신은 작은 여우입니다.
You can't be furless.
모피가 없을 수는 없습니다.
A bald fox will be mocked.
대머리 여우가 조롱을 당할 것이다.
I'll be hairless.
나는 털이 없을 것이다.
Getting bald.
대머리가 되는 중.
I am a little fox without a name.
나는 이름없는 작은 여우입니다.
But my little fox must have a name.
하지만 내 작은 여우에게는 이름이 있어야 해요.
Foxes cry like Wu…
여우는 우처럼 울어요…
So I'll call you
그럼 내가 전화할게
Wu.
우.
Yelp.
개가 깽깽 우는 소리.
Yelp for me.
나를 위해 옐프.
So naughty.
너무 장난 꾸러기.
I'll spank you.
나는 당신을 때릴 것이다.
Yelp. Come on.
개가 깽깽 우는 소리. 어서 해봐요.
It hurts.
아파요.
I can't go on fooling around.
계속 장난을 칠 수는 없어요.
It's time to grow up.
이제 성장할 시간입니다.
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
I'll miss you.
나는 당신을 그리워할 것이다.
Don't be sad.
슬퍼하지 마세요.
Don't cry.
울지 마세요.
I will always be with you.
나는 항상 당신과 함께 있을 것입니다.
Don't be sad. Don't cry.
슬퍼하지 마세요. 울지 마세요.
Wu.
우.
Is that you?
당신인가요?
Don't be sad. Don't cry.
슬퍼하지 마세요. 울지 마세요.
I will always be with you.
나는 항상 당신과 함께 있을 것입니다.
Don't be sad.
슬퍼하지 마세요.
Don't cry.
울지 마세요.
I will always be with you.
나는 항상 당신과 함께 있을 것입니다.
Don't be sad. Don't cry.
슬퍼하지 마세요. 울지 마세요.
The past can't be changed.
과거는 바꿀 수 없습니다.
Trapped in this doll,
이 인형 안에 갇혀
she had to sever her spiritual tail
그녀는 영적인 꼬리를 잘라야 했어
and unleash all her power to make a faint sound
그리고 그녀의 모든 힘을 발휘해 보세요. 희미한 소리를 내다
through that doll to stop you from committing suicide.
그 인형을 통해서 널 막으려고 자살부터.
She is not only my moon,
그녀는 나의 달일 뿐만 아니라,
but she has also always been my little fox.
하지만 그녀도 그랬어 언제나 나의 작은 여우였어.
After that,
그 후
you had a little talking fox keeping you company
너 말하는 여우가 좀 있었어 당신과 함께 지내요
and you were no longer lonely.
그리고 당신은 더 이상 외롭지 않았습니다.
You gave up the idea of suicide and gathered the courage
당신은 자살에 대한 생각을 포기했습니다 그리고 용기를 냈어요
to become the Dragon Deity step by step.
차근차근 용신이 되기 위해.
But the fox doll
그런데 여우 인형은
never spoke again.
다시는 말을 하지 않았습니다.
You told people about it,
당신은 그것에 대해 사람들에게 말했습니다.
but nobody believed it.
그러나 아무도 그것을 믿지 않았습니다.
How can a rag doll comfort you?
헝겊 인형이 어떻게 당신을 위로할 수 있습니까?
Don't tell me it can talk.
그것이 말할 수 있다고 말하지 마세요.
It really talks.
정말 말이에요.
After that,
그 후
you created Ji Ling with the spell of Severed Silk.
당신이 Ji Ling을 만들었습니다 잘린 실크의 주문으로.
You gave him the little fox
당신은 그에게 작은 여우를 주었습니다
and sent him out to wander the world.
그를 세상을 방황하도록 보냈습니다.
Then he met Lu Wuyi.
그런 다음 그는 Lu Wuyi를 만났습니다.
The universe is vast and exquisite.
우주는 광대하고 절묘합니다.
Even I find it hard
나조차도 힘들다
to perceive everything.
모든 것을 인식하는 것.
It turns out
알고보니
the beginning of the story
이야기의 시작
has already been altered by Wu.
이미 Wu에 의해 변경되었습니다.
Lu Wuyi once asked me
한때 Lu Wuyi가 나에게 물어본 적이 있습니다
why I would help her go back in time.
내가 왜 그녀가 시간을 되돌릴 수 있도록 도와야 하는지.
I said I wasn't helping her.
나는 그녀를 돕지 않는다고 말했습니다.
The person I wanted to help
내가 돕고 싶었던 사람
was you.
당신이었나요?
Your ending was never to die by your own hand,
너의 결말은 결코 네 손으로 죽는 거야,
nor to sacrifice yourself to that drought.
그 가뭄에 자신을 희생하지도 않습니다.
The end of your life
인생의 마지막
has always been
항상
to be devoured by me.
나에게 삼켜지려고.
We must go back in time to keep you from loneliness
우리는 시간을 거슬러 올라가야 해 당신을 외로움으로부터 보호하기 위해
so that I never come to life.
그래서 나는 결코 살아나지 않습니다.
That is the only way to change your fate.
그것이 당신의 운명을 바꿀 수 있는 유일한 방법이다.
Why would you sacrifice yourself
왜 자신을 희생하려 합니까
to save me?
나를 구하기 위해?
Because you are a kind person.
당신은 친절한 사람이기 때문입니다.
But for a hundred years,
하지만 100년 동안
no one in this world has truly loved you
이 세상 어느 누구도 당신을 진심으로 사랑한 적이 없어요
or been willing to die for you.
아니면 당신을 위해 기꺼이 죽을 수도 있습니다.
Is there anyone who loves you enough to die for you?
당신을 충분히 사랑하는 사람이 있나요 당신을 위해 죽겠다고요?
Is there?
거기 있나요?
Now there is.
이제 있습니다.
She loves you enough
그녀는 당신을 충분히 사랑해요
to die for you.
당신을 위해 죽는 것.
So, I should disappear.
그러니 나는 사라져야 한다.
But the ending is written.
그러나 결말은 기록되어 있습니다.
This is too cruel for you.
이것은 당신에게 너무 잔인합니다.
She only exists
그녀는 오직 존재한다
because of Jiu Ying.
지영 때문에.
Once Jiu Ying dies, she will also perish.
Jiu Ying이 죽으면 그녀도 멸망할 것입니다.
But the meaning of your existence
하지만 당신의 존재 의미는
is to annihilate Jiu Ying.
Jiu Ying을 전멸시키는 것입니다.
The last Dragon Deity's Power in this world
마지막 용신의 힘 이 세상에서는
has been destroyed.
파괴되었습니다.
I don't have
난 없어
to reach the end.
끝까지 도달하기 위해.
I used to be a dragon scale.
나는 용의 비늘이었습니다.
Therefore,
따라서
I carry the last Dragon Deity's Power in this world.
나는 마지막 용신의 힘을 품고 있다 이 세상에서.
You can use it to kill Jiu Ying
Jiu Ying을 죽이는 데 사용할 수 있습니다
or to save Lu Wuyi.
아니면 Lu Wuyi를 구하기 위해.
This final decision
이번 최종 결정
is up to you.
그것은 당신에게 달려 있습니다.
Jiu Ying sent her to you
Jiu Ying이 그녀를 당신에게 보냈습니다
to make you fall in love with her
당신이 그녀와 사랑에 빠지게 만들기 위해
so that you would struggle
당신이 어려움을 겪도록
between love and duty.
사랑과 의무 사이
This is what it means to be the fated one.
운명적인 사람이 된다는 것은 이런 의미입니다.
Between you and her,
당신과 그녀 사이에서,
one must live,
살아야 해,
and one shall perish.
한 사람은 멸망할 것이다.
Commander Li.
리 사령관.
It's so late. Why are you here?
너무 늦었어요. 당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
I want to see Master Dragon Deity.
마스터 드래곤 신을 보고 싶어요.
Master Dragon Deity is in the Scale Cave.
Master Dragon Deity는 비늘 동굴에 있습니다.
Go ahead, please.
계속하세요.
I won't let you hurt Master Dragon Deity.
나는 당신이 마스터 드래곤 디티를 해치게 두지 않을 것입니다.
You are just like your grandfather, Ye Daoxuan.
당신은 할아버지와 똑같습니다. 예 Daoxuan.
You'd protect him at the cost of your lives.
당신은 그를 보호할 것입니다 당신의 생명을 희생하여.
Why did you come here?
왜 여기에 왔나요?
To kill him.
그를 죽이려고.
The fourth Dragon Deity's Power has been destroyed.
네 번째 용신의 힘 파괴되었습니다.
Wu Shiguang can never transform into a dragon.
우시광은 절대 못해 드래곤으로 변신합니다.
And Ji Ling will remain a false deity,
그리고 Ji Ling은 거짓 신으로 남을 것입니다.
suffering loneliness forever.
영원히 외로움을 겪는다.
What a cruel fate.
얼마나 잔인한 운명인가.
I must set him free.
나는 그를 풀어주어야 한다.
Triple-flower paints the day. All things live and perish.
삼중꽃은 하루를 그린다. 모든 것은 살고 멸망합니다.
Before me, all becomes clear.
내 앞에서는 모든 것이 명확해진다.
Break!
부서지다!
You're actually using the demon power preserved for the inner core.
당신은 실제로 악마의 힘을 사용하고 있습니다. 내부 코어를 위해 보존되었습니다.
Do you have a death wish?
죽고 싶은 마음이 있나요?
My life is yours.
내 인생은 당신 것입니다.
But he
하지만 그는
must remain alive.
살아있어야 합니다.
Bai Ze.
바이 제.
Do you think you can beat me with your petty tricks?
네가 나를 이길 수 있을 것 같아? 당신의 사소한 속임수로?
Ye Changsheng. Well done.
예 창성. 잘하셨어요.
What did you do?
당신은 무엇을 했나요?
Take my Purple Lightning Chain.
내 보라색 번개 사슬을 가져가세요.
If you see Yuan Wuhuo, find a way to merge this with his blade.
Yuan Wuhuo를 본다면, 이것을 그의 칼날과 합칠 방법을 찾아보세요.
Young men of the Shilin Sect
스린파의 청년들
use faith as shields and courage as spears
믿음을 방패로, 용기를 창으로 삼아
to protect the Dragon Deity and the world
용신과 세계를 보호하기 위해
until the last minute.
마지막 순간까지.
Ye Daoxuan.
예 다오쉬안.
Ye Mingshan.
예 밍샨.
Ye Changsheng.
예 창성.
The devotion to the Shilin Sect lives on.
스린종에 대한 헌신은 계속되고 있습니다.
Thus, light and hope will never leave this world.
그래서 빛과 희망 결코 이 세상을 떠나지 않을 것입니다.
Yuan Wuhuo.
위안우후오.
Your sins
당신의 죄
end with me today.
오늘 나랑 끝내자.
Little fox.
작은 여우.
I have to go.
나는 가야 해요.
I hope you don't
그러지 않기를 바라요
feel lonely again.
다시 외로움을 느낀다.
The fifth gem.
다섯 번째 보석.
Ji Can, the Lonescale.
론스케일 지칸.